More entertaining than humanly possible!
The Muppet Movie is a family, comedy, adventure film directed by James Frawley.
The Muppets gather to watch their newly-finished big-budget rich-and-famous feature film: a talent
agent persuades Kermit the Frog to leave the swamp to pursue a career in Hollywood.
On his way there, he meets a bear, a pig, a whatever (his future muppet crew), and some special
celebrity guest stars, while being chased by the desperate owner of a frog-leg restaurant!
Kermit the Frog / Rowlf / Dr. Teeth / Waldorf / Doc Hopper's Men / Link
Hogthrob / Swedish Chef (voice), played by Jim Henson.
Miss Piggy / Fozzie Bear / Animal / Sam the Eagle / Doc Hopper's Men / Marvin Suggs /
Swedish Chef (hands) / Motorcycle Guy (voice), played by Frank Oz.
Floyd Pepper / Robin the Frog / Crazy Harry / Lew Zealand / Camilla / Dr.
Bunsen Honeydew (assistant) (voice), played by Jerry Nelson.
Scooter / Statler / Janice / Sweetums / Beaker / Fozzie Bear
(assistant) (voice), played by Richard Hunt.
The Great Gonzo / Dr. Bunsen Honeydew / Zoot / Doglion / Iraqian in
El Sleezo Cafe / Pig (voice), played by Dave Goelz.
Doc Hopper, played by Charles Durning.
The Muppet Movie is a 1979 musical road comedy film, directed by James Frawley and
produced by Jim Henson, and the first theatrical film to feature the Muppets.
A co-production between the United Kingdom and the United States, the film was
written by The Muppet Show writers Jerry Juhl and Jack Burns.
Produced during the third season of The Muppet Show, the film tells the origin story of the Muppets, as Kermit the Frog embarks on a cross-country trip to Los Angeles, encountering several of the Muppets—who all share the
same ambition of finding success in professional show business—along the way while being pursued by Doc Hopper, a greedy restaurateur with intentions of recruiting Kermit to promote his frog legs business.
The film stars Muppet performers Henson, Frank Oz, Jerry Nelson, Richard Hunt, and Dave Goelz, as well as Charles Durning and Austin Pendleton, and it features cameo appearances by Bob Hope, Dom DeLuise, James Coburn, Cloris
Leachman, Richard Pryor, Telly Savalas, Edgar Bergen (in his final film appearance before his death), Orson Welles, Madeline Kahn, Milton Berle, Carol Kane, Steve Martin, Mel Brooks, Elliott Gould, and Paul Williams.
Notable for its surreal humour, meta-references and prolific use of cameos, The Muppet Movie was released by Universal Pictures
and Associated Film Distribution in the United Kingdom on May 31, 1979, and in the United States on June 22, 1979.
The film received critical praise, including two Academy Award nominations for Paul
Williams and Kenneth Ascher's musical score and their song "Rainbow Connection".
The film grossed $65.2 million worldwide against an $8 million budget.
The Muppet Movie was followed by seven feature films starring the
Muppets as well as several more television series and media.
In 2009, the film was deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant" by the
Library of Congress and selected for preservation in the National Film Registry.
The film explores themes of chicken, musical, puppet, road trip, fame.
The tone is lighthearted.